<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;प्रकीर्णम् on माध्व-मते विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/mAdhvam/tattvam/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;प्रकीर्णम् on माध्व-मते विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/mAdhvam/tattvam/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>व्यासाः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/mAdhvam/tattvam/misc/vyAsAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/mAdhvam/tattvam/misc/vyAsAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: अश्विनीकुमारः, supposedly not from AI, but suspected to be so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kṛṣṇa Dvaipāyana Vyāsa is not an āveśa avatāra; rather, he is a svāṁśa avatāra. You may ask What is the pramāṇa to consider Kṛṣṇa Dvaipāyana as not a jīva, but Viṣṇu-tattva?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This question does not arise, because only his birth is glorified as svāṁśa avatāra, and there is no statement specifying him as a jīva. कृष्णद्वैपायनं व्यासं विद्धि नारायणं प्रभुम् । Instead, Scriptures do not mention others like Bṛhaspati or aswathama as swayam Narayana. Only Satyavatī-Pārāśara-suta and Hari is glorified as Svayam Nārāyaṇa. Also, there are statements in the śāstras which describe how Kṛṣṇa Dvaipāyana deluded the demons and made them think of him as a jīva with doshas. You do not find this for others. Neither Bṛhaspati nor Aśvatthāmā will be reborn as Vyāsa. They are Chirañjīvi.  Instead, they are empowered by Vyāsa-rūpa Bhagavān to act on his behalf.  Also, the śāstras do not mention Kṛṣṇa Dvaipāyana, Hari as a common jīva without āveśa before becoming Vyasa, unlike Aśvatthāmā and Bṛhaspati. In contrast, others have different stories explaining how they were elevated to Vyāsa-pada.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
